A Finding Aid to the Terence Harold Robsjohn-Gibbings Papers in the Archives of American Art AAA.robstere
Archives of American Art
Terence Harold Robsjohn-Gibbings papers
1915-1977
1898
AAA.robstere
Archives of American Art
13.4 Linear feet
The papers of furniture and interior designer Terence Harold Robsjohn-Gibbings measure 13.4 linear feet and date from 1898 to 1977 with the bulk of material dating from 1915 to 1977. Found within the papers are biographical material, correspondence, writings, project files, printed materials, artwork including 4 sketchbooks, 30 scrapbooks documenting Robsjohn-Gibbings career, and photographs of Robsjohn-Gibbings and his work.
Robsjohn-Gibbings, Terence Harold, b. 1905
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Portions of the Terence Robsjohn-Gibbings papers were donated by the artist in 1966. In 1977, Margaret Carson donated a manuscript copy of The Cuckoo Sings. Later in 1977, the bulk of additional material in the collection was donated to the Archives of American Art by Robsjohn-Gibbing's associate and executor, Carlton Pullin.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Biographical/Historical note
Terence Harold Robsjohn-Gibbings (1905-1976) was a furniture and interior designer who lived and worked in New York City and Athens, Greece.
Robsjohn-Gibbings was born in England and studied architecture at London University. In 1930, he immigrated to America and six years later opened his own interior decorating firm, Robsjohn-Gibbings Ltd., on Madison Avenue. Throughout the 1940s and 50s, he was one of the most recognized decorators in America and designed homes for Doris Duke, Alfred Knopf, and Thelma Chrysler Foy. One of his earliest commissions was Hilda Boldt Weber’s 43 room Casa Encantada mansion in Bel-Air, for which he created more than 200 custom pieces of furniture between 1934 and 1938.
From 1943 to 1956, Robsjohn-Gibbings was the principal designer for the Widdicomb Furniture Company in Grand Rapids, Michigan. These residential furnishings reflected an elegant, simplistic aesthetic and were regularly showcased in the magazines Town and Country, Interior Design, Vogue, and House Beautiful.
He was a critic of the prevailing taste in Bauhaus modernism and Queen Anne, Georgian, and Spanish extravagance and expressed these views on design and aesthetics in the books Goodbye, Mr. Chippendale (1944), Mona Lisa’s Moustache (1947), and Homes of the Brave (1953).
In 1960, he and his collaborator, Carlton Pullin, met the Greek furniture makers Susan and Eleftherios Saridis, who commissioned Robsjohn-Gibbings to design a line for their company, Saridis of Athens. These pieces were modeled after classical Greek forms and aesthetics, and are detailed in Robsjohn-Gibbings’ Furniture of Classical Greece (1963).
In 1965, Robsjohn-Gibbings moved to Athens, Greece and continued designing residential and commercial spaces until his death in 1976.
Scope and Contents note
The papers of furniture and interior designer Terence Harold Robsjohn-Gibbings measure 13.4 linear feet and date from 1898 to 1977, with the bulk of material dating from 1915 to 1977. Found within the papers are biographical material, correspondence, writings, project files, printed materials, artwork including 4 sketchbooks, 30 scrapbooks documenting Robsjohn-Gibbings career, and photographs of Robsjohn-Gibbings and his work.
Biographical materials consist of a key to the city of San Francisco, an award certificate, a photograph of a table from Robsjohn-Gibbings' personal art collection, and a ring design.
Correspondence is primarily with Robsjohn-Gibbings’ friends, business associates, and scholarly researchers discussing relationships, business commissions, and his professional work. Correspondents of note include illustrators Alan Dunn and Mary Petty, and classical art historian Gisela Richter.
Writings by Robsjohn-Gibbings consist of 13 essays, 2 copies of the draft manuscript The Cuckoo Sings, 2 manuscript drafts of Furniture of Classical Greece, and a notebook of collected inspirational quotations. There is also a translation of a selection of Heinz Kahler’s Hadrian und Seine Villa Bei Tivoli.
Project files include photographs and portfolios of 28 commercial and residential commissions; photographs and watercolor renderings of designs produced by Robsjohn-Gibbings Ltd.; photographs and portfolios of designs for Widdicomb Furniture Company; and printed material and research related to the furniture designs for Saridis of Athens. The series also includes portfolios of residences photographed by Ezra Stoller Associates, and photographs and notes for a 25 year Interior Design retrospective exhibition.
Printed material includes published books by Robsjohn-Gibbings, annotated books on Hadrian’s Villa and decorative sculpture, catalogs, clippings, press releases, and miscellaneous printed material.
Photographs are of Robsjohn-Gibbings, his friends, his New York office and Athens apartment, and photo shoots for Life and Look magazines.
There are 24 volumes documenting Robsjohn-Gibbings career from 1936 to 1963, an additional 4 volumes of press coverage of his books, and 2 more volumes documenting European art and historical interior design.
Artwork includes 4 sketchbooks of classical Greek and Roman furniture designs rendered in graphite and watercolor by Robsjohn-Gibbings.
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged as 8 series.
Series 1: Biographical Materials, 1942-1970 (4 folders, Box 1)
Series 2: Correspondence, circa 1940-1976 (0.2 linear feet; Box 1)
Series 3: Writings, circa 1930-1976 (0.5 linear feet; Box 1, BV 12)
Series 4: Project Files, circa 1930-1976 (4 linear feet; Box 1-2, Box 6-8, BV 13-16, OV 42-53, OV 55)
Series 5: Printed Material, 1898-1977 (1.9 linear feet, Box 2-4, Box 9)
Series 6: Photographic Materials, 1915-1976 (0.3 linear feet; Box 4, Box 9, OV 54)
Series 7: Scrapbooks, 1936-1970 (5.9 linear feet, Box 9-11, BV 17-41)
Series 8: Artwork, circa 1930-1976 (0.5 linear feet; Box 4-5, Box 9)
Dunn, Alan, 1900-; Hadrian's Villa. (Tivoli, Italy); Hadrian, Emperor of Rome, 76-138, Homes and haunts--Italy--Tivoli; Petty, Mary; Richter, Gisela Marie Augusta, 1882-1972; Robsjohn-Gibbings (Firm).; Decorative arts; Furniture design--United States; Furniture designers--New York (State)--New York; Interior decorators -- New York (State) -- New York; Photographs; Scrapbooks; Sketchbooks
- Biographical Materials, 1942-1970; Series 1; 4 Folders Box 1
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical materials consist of a key to the city of San Francisco presented by Mayor George Christopher, an award certificate from New York University, a photograph of a table from Robsjohn-Gibbings' personal art collection, and a ring design.
  Arrangement note
  Materials are arranged by document type.
  - Award, San Francisco Key to the City, circa 1956-1964 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Certificate, New York University, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Personal Art Collection, circa 1940-1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ring Design, circa 1940-1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, circa 1940-1976; Series 2; 0.2 Linear feet Box 1
  Correspondence is primarily with Robsjohn-Gibbings’ friends, business associates, and scholarly researchers discussing relationships, business commissions, and his professional work. Correspondents of note include illustrators and close friends Alan Dunn and Mary Petty, and classical art historian Gisela Richter.
  Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  - A-Z Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - AC and R Public Relations, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Dunn, Alan and Mary Petty, circa 1960-1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Pahlman, William, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Richter, Gisela M. A., 1963-1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Scalamandré Silks, Inc., 1963-1966 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Schwartz, George H., 1964-1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Sotheby and Co., 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Story, Ala, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Urban Furniture Company, Inc., 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 14-15)
  - Weale, Mary Jo, 1967-1974 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Writings, circa 1930-1976; Series 3; 0.5 Linear feet Box 1, BV 12
  Writings by Robsjohn-Gibbings consist of 13 typescript essays, 2 copies of the draft The Cuckoo Sings, 2 drafts of Furniture of Classical Greece, and a notebook of collected inspirational quotations. One draft of Furniture of Classical Greece is a bound volume mockup layout for the forthcoming book. There is also a translation of a selection of Heinz Kahler’s Hadrian und Seine Villa Bei Tivoli.
  Materials are arranged by author and document type.
  - Writings by Robsjohn-Gibbings (Box 1)
    - Draft, Cuckoo Sings, circa 1970-1976 (Box 1, Folder 17-18)
    - Draft, Cuckoo Sings (copy), circa 1970-1976 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Draft, Furniture of Classical Greece, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Oversized material in BV 12.
    - Essay, "Art No. 1 Bore", circa 1940-1970 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Essay, "Clutter, A Lost Art", circa 1940-1970 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Essay, "Consoeurs of Architecture", circa 1940-1970 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Essay, "Dear Olde Avante-Garde", circa 1940-1970 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Essay, "For Great Ladies Only", circa 1940-1970 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Essay, "Last of the Red-Hot Moderns", circa 1940-1970 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Essay, "New Taste", circa 1940-1970 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Essay, "No Taste: Today's New Recipe for Decorative Elegance", circa 1940-1970 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Essay, "Timeless Design", circa 1940-1970 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Essay, "Ungracious Living", circa 1940-1970 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Essay, "Water, Water, Everywhere", circa 1940-1970 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Essay, "You Can't Put Your Feet Up On a Mondrian", circa 1940-1970 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Essay, "Comfort and Amenities", 1957 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Notebook, Quotations, circa 1930-1976 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Oversized Volume, Draft, Furniture of Classical Greece, 1963 (Box BV 12)
      Oversized material from Box 1, F20.
  - Writings by Others (Box 1)
    - Kahler, Heinz, Hadrian und Seine Villa Bei Tivoli, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Project Files, circa 1940-1976; Series 4; 4 Linear feet Box 6-8, BV 13-16, OV 42-53, OV 55
  Project files include photographs and portfolios of 28 commercial and residential commissions; photographs and original display sized watercolor renderings of interior designs and furniture produced by Robsjohn-Gibbings Ltd.; photographs and portfolios of room and furniture designs for Widdicomb Furniture Company; and printed material and research related to the furniture designs for Saridis of Athens. The series also includes portfolios of residences photographed by Ezra Stoller Associates, and photographs and notes for a 25 year Interior Design retrospective exhibition. Many of the photographs found in this series were taken by architectural photographers Maynard Parker, Ezra Stoller, William Howland, and Richard Garrison.
  Materials are arranged by project category.
  - Exhibition, Interior Design 25 Year Retrospective, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    Oversized material housed in OV 42.
  - Furniture, circa 1960-1970 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    Oversized material housed in Box 6, F1 and BV 13.
  - Furniture, Custom Made, 1936-1950 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Commercial, E.P. Nomikos Offices, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Commercial, Grand Central Palace, Marble Room, circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Commercial, John Frederics, Inc., 1939 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Commercial, Museum of Modern Art, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Commercial, National Home Furnishings Show, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Commercial, Nieman Marcus, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    Oversized material housed in Box 6, F2.
  - Commercial, Paul Flato Studio, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    Oversized material housed in Box 6, F3.
  - Commercial, River Club, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    Oversized material housed in Box 6, F4.
  - Residence, Apartment (first in New York City), circa 1930-1950 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Residence, Annenberg House, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Residence, Mr. and Mrs. Thomas B. Davis, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    Oversized material housed in Box 6, F5-6.
  - Residence, Diamond House, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Residence, Mrs. Byron C. Foy, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    Oversized material housed in Box 6, F7 and BV 14.
  - Residence, Mr. and Mrs. B.T. Gale, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    Oversized material housed in Box 6, F8-9.
  - Residence, Gamz House, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Residence, Goulandris House, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Residence, Mr. and Mrs. Bruno K. Graf, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 55-56)
    Oversized material housed in Box 7, F1.
  - Residence, Hudson House, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Residence, Herbert Johnson, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Residence, Kandell House, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Residence, Blanche Knopf, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Oversized material housed in Box 7, F2.
  - Residence, Mrs. Fernand Leval, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Oversized material housed in Box 7, F3.
  - Residence, Maitland House, circa 1940-1970 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Residence, Mr. and Mrs. Harvey S. Mudd, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Residence, Parten House, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Oversized material housed in Box 7, F4.
  - Residence, Mr. and Mrs. Lewis Ruskin, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Oversized material housed in Box 7, F5-6.
  - Residence, Simons House, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Residence, Weber House, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Oversized material housed in Box 7, F7.
  - Research, Hadrian's Villa, Article by Robsjohn-Gibbings, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Research, Hadrian's Villa, Renderings and Photographs, circa 1950-1970 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Oversized material housed in OV 42 and OV 55.
  - Research, Hadrian's Villa, Clippings, circa 1950-1970 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Research, Hadrian's Villa, Postcards of Ruins, circa 1950-1970 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Research, Hadrian's Villa, Postcards of Statuary, circa 1950-1970 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Research, Hadrian's Villa, Photographs of Statuary, circa 1950-1970 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Research, Hadrian's Villa, Miscellaneous Printed Material, circa 1950-1970 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Research, Olynthus, Clippings, 1934-1966 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Research, Olynthus, Photographs, circa 1950-1970 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Ezra Stoller Associates, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Oversized material housed in BV 15-16.
  - Robsjohn-Gibbings Ltd., circa 1940-1970 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Oversized material housed in Box 8, F1 and OV 43-53.
  - Saridis, Brochures, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Saridis, Catalogs, circa 1972 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Saridis, Clippings, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Widdicomb Furnishings, Bureaus, circa 1950-1960 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Widdicomb Furnishings, Chairs, circa 1950-1960 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Widdicomb Furnishings, Tables, circa 1950-1960 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Widdicomb Furnishings, Dining and Bedrooms, circa 1950-1960 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Widdicomb Furnishings, Living Rooms, circa 1950-1960 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Widdicomb Portfolios, #1-4, circa 1950-1960 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    Oversized material housed in Box 8, F2-5.
  - Widdicomb, Residential Interior Design, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    Oversized material housed in Box 8, F6.
  - Widdicomb, Catalogs, circa 1940-1960 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Widdicomb, Miscellaneous Printed Material, circa 1950-1960 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Oversized Photographs, Furniture, circa 1960-1970 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Oversized material from Box 1, F37.
  - Oversized Photographs, Commercial, Nieman-Marcus, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Oversized material from Box 1, F44.
  - Oversized Photographs, Commercial, Paul Flato Studio, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Oversized material from Box 1, F45.
  - Oversized Photographs, Commercial, River Club, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Oversized material from Box 1, F46.
  - Oversized Photographs and Portfolio, Residential, Mr. and Mrs. Thomas B. Davis, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 5-6)
    Oversized material from Box 1, F49.
  - Oversized Photographs, Residence, Mrs. Byron C. Foy, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    Oversized material from Box 1, F51.
  - Oversized Photographs and Portfolio, Residence, Mr. and Mrs. B.T. Gale, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 8-9)
    Oversized material from Box 1, F52.
  - Oversized Photographs, Residence, Mr. and Mrs. Bruno K. Graf, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Oversized material from Box 1, F55.
  - Oversized Photographs, Residence, Blanche Knopf, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Oversized material from Box 2, F4.
  - Oversized Photographs, Residence, Mrs. Fernand Leval, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    Oversized material from Box 2, F5.
  - Oversized Photographs, Residence, Parten House, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Oversized material from Box 2, F8.
  - Oversized Photographs and Portfolio, Residence, Mr. and Mrs. Lewis Ruskin, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
    Oversized material from Box 2, F9.
  - Oversized Photographs, Residence, Weber House, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Oversized material from Box 2, F11.
  - Oversized Photographs, Robsjohn-Gibbings, Ltd., circa 1940-1970 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Oversized material from Box 2, F22.
  - Oversized Photographs and Portfolios, Widdicomb, circa 1950s (Box 8, Folder 2-6)
    Oversized material from Box 2, F31-32.
  - Oversized Photographs, Exhibition Retrospective and Research on Hadrian's Villa, circa 1960-1970 (Box OV 42)
    Oversized material from Box 1, F36 and Box 2, F13 and F18.
  - Oversized Renderings, Robsjohn-Gibbings Ltd., circa 1940-1970 (Box OV 43-53)
  - Oversized Renderings, Research on Hadrian's Villa, circa 1950-1970 (Box OV 55)
    Oversized material from Box 2, F13.
  - Oversized Volume, Photographs of Furniture, circa 1960-1970 (Box BV 13)
  - Oversized Volume, Residence, Mrs. Byron C. Foy, 1943 (Box BV 14)
  - Oversized Volumes, Ezra Stoller Associates, 1952 (Box BV 15-16)
    Oversized material from Box 2, F21.
- Printed Material, 1898-1977; Series 5; 1.9 Linear feet Box 2-4, Box 9
  Printed material includes Goodbye, Mr. Chippendale and Homes of the Brave by Robsjohn-Gibbings, 15 annotated books on Hadrian’s Villa and decorative sculpture, catalogs, clippings, press releases, and miscellaneous printed material.
  - Books by Robsjohn-Gibbings (Box 2)
    - Good-Bye, Mr. Chippendale, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Homes of the Brave, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Books on Hadrian (Box 2-3)
    - Die Bildnisse des Antinous, by Christoph Clairmont, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Emperor Hadrian, by Ferdinand Gregorovius, 1898 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Hadrian, by Stewart Perowne, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Hadrian, by Max Wegner, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Hadrian: und Seine Villa Bei Tivoli, by Heinz Kähler, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Hadrianic School, by Jocelyn Toynbee, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Hadrian's Villa, by Pierre Gusman, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Life and Principate of the Emperor Hadrian, A.D. 76-138, by Bernard Henderson, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Magnificent Hadrian, by Sulamith ish-Kishor, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Memoirs of Hadrian, by Marguerite Yourcenar, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Rome and A Villa, by Eleanor Clark, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Books on Design and Sculpture (Box 4)
    - Villa Adriana, by Salvatore Aurigemma, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Decorative Thirties, by Martin Battersby, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Furniture of the Greeks, Etruscans, and Romans, by G.M. Richter, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Kama Kala, by Mulk Raj Anand, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Catalogs, Auctions and Books, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1940-1977 (Box 4, Folder 6-10)
    Oversized material housed in Box 9, F1.
  - Clippings, Greek, circa 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Press Releases, 1961-1963 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Program, Hellenic-American Chamber of Commerce Dinner, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, circa 1950-1970 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Oversized Clippings, circa 1970-1977 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Oversized material from Box 4, F10.
- Photographic Materials, 1915-1976; Series 6; 0.3 Linear feet Box 4, Box 9, OV 54
  Photographic materials are of Robsjohn-Gibbings; his friends, including collaborator and partner Carlton Pullin; his New York office and Athens apartment; and photo shoots for Life and Look magazines.
  Materials are arranged by subject and item type.
  - Photographs of Robsjohn-Gibbings, 1915-1976 (Box 4, Folder 15-18)
    Oversized material housed in Box 9, F2 and OV 54.
  - Transparencies of Robsjohn-Gibbings with Chairs, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Photographs of Robsjohn-Gibbings with Friends, 1940-1970 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Photographs of Robsjohn-Gibbings' Athens Apartment, circa 1960-1976 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Photographs of Robsjohn-Gibbings Ltd. Studio, 1948-1963 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Photographs of Life Magazine Photo Shoot, Living Room, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Photographs of Life Magazine Photo Shoot, Greece, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Photographs of Look Magazine Photo Shoot, Bathroom, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Oversized Photographs of Robsjohn-Gibbings, 1915-1976 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    Oversized material from Box 4, F15, F17-18.
  - Oversized Photograph of Robsjohn-Gibbings, circa 1940-1949 (Box OV 54)
    Oversized material from Box 4, F17.
- Scrapbooks, 1936-1970; Series 7; 5.9 Linear feet Box 9-11, BV 17-41
  Scrapbooks consist of 24 volumes documenting Robsjohn-Gibbings career from 1936 to 1963, 4 volumes of press coverage of his books, and 2 volumes documenting European art and historical interior design. Clippings comprise the bulk of the material found in these scrapbooks, though occasional letters, cards, photographs, and other ephemera are included. The 2 volumes documenting European art and historical interior design are all clippings from published materials.
  Items have been arranged by topic.
  - Scrapbook #1, Robsjohn-Gibbings, 1936-1938 (Box 9)
  - Scrapbook #2-3, Robsjohn-Gibbings, 1939-1941 (Box 10)
  - Scrapbook #4-5, Robsjohn-Gibbings, 1941-1945 (Box 11)
  - Scrapbook #6-10, Robsjohn-Gibbings, 1946-1951 (Box BV 17-21)
  - Scrapbook #11-15, Robsjohn-Gibbings, 1950-1953 (Box BV 22-26)
  - Scrapbook #16-20, Robsjohn-Gibbings, 1953-1955 (Box BV 27-31)
  - Scrapbook #21-24, Robsjohn-Gibbings, 1957-1963 (Box BV 32-35)
  - Scrapbook #25, Clippings, Goodbye Mr. Chippendale, 1944 (Box BV 36)
  - Scrapbook #26, Clippings, Homes of the Brave, 1954 (Box BV 37)
  - Scrapbook #27-28, Clippings, Mona Lisa's Moustache, 1947-1949 (Box BV 38-39)
  - Scrapbook #29, European Art and Iconography, 1953 (Box BV 40)
  - Scrapbook #30, Historical Interior Design, circa 1930-1970 (Box BV 41)
- Artwork, circa 1930-1976; Series 8; 0.5 Linear feet Box 4-5, Box 9
  Artwork consists of 4 sketchbooks containing several hundred classical Greek and Roman furniture designs rendered in graphite and watercolor by Robsjohn-Gibbings, and 1 sketch of Robsjohn-Gibbings' feet.
  Materials are arranged by item type and subject.
  - Sketch, Drawing of Feet, circa 1940-1970 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Sketchbook, Original Designs for Furniture Based on Greek Models, circa 1940-1970 (Box 4, Folder 28-29)
  - Sketchbook, Drawings of Greek and Roman Bronze Lamps, Handles, and Furniture, circa 1940-1970 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Sketchbook, Drawings of Original Greek Furniture. Reconstructed, circa 1940-1970 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Sketchbook, Portfolio, circa 1940-1976 (Box 9, Folder 3)